ICS a Lombard compan is reported a 68%
jump in net profit while commission
ratio saw a spike we spoke to the
management on their quarter
listening let me just put this in
context uh so again if you look at uh
from an ISU Lombard standpoint what we
have largely spoken about is uh to
continue to drive profitable growth as a
theme and that is what we have kind of
stayed on um across various years of
operations in terms of how we have run
businesses at um so that's the same
thing that's kind of helping us uh so
for example if you look at uh couple of
years back when the market was very very
aggressive obviously we took a guarded
SL cautious approach to writing risks
and therefore to that extent uh I think
uh we have been able to possibly see a
downward slope uh in the overall
combined ratios for ICA Lombard and in
that context is how you should look at
even the current quarter SL 9 Monon
numbers uh so pretty much on track in
terms of the thought process or the
gliding path that we have spoken maybe
almost about four years back uh in terms
of where do we want to see the combined
ises for I play out at the factors I
think clearly it's a combination of I
would say three or four elements uh so
one maybe let me start at the macro
level which is I think the regulatory
environment has been very very enabling
and therefore for to that extent uh that
aids the market at large and of course
for companies who are very very careful
in terms of how they want to kind of
write the risk set so hence I think we
have had a favorable regulatory
environment that's kind of aided Us in
terms of the outcomes that one has seen
But when you have to come to specifics I
think uh the combin ratio Improvement
what you see in terms of the glid
gliding numbers uh has kind of come
through uh our shared focus on uh
continuing to drive profitable growth in
terms of Top Line and equally I think we
have we have taken a lot of initiatives
in terms of uh claims management and
finally I would say at the end of the
day what we keep looking for is to see
how we can be far more efficient in
terms of operations and hence a
combination of all the three factors are
where they are in terms of the outcome
on combined I think the only caveat that
I would put is uh increasingly we are
seeing for the industry a lot of
catastrophic events and that's very
difficult to kind of predict and
therefore to that extent in terms of
outcomes I think at different quarters
depending on how these events play out
the combination for the industry and
even for Isis lard could take shape
appropriately H okay so at this point
you know your combined uh your combined
ratio is at
102.7 uh would that
be only better going forward is that the
Outlook uh the way you see it
so let me just again put this in context
I think the reported combin of 102.7
that you're referring to is let's say
for quarter 3 now that obviously has got
uh a slight Nuance a Nuance in the
context of again a regulatory change
effectively first October all long-term
products as for the regulatory
stipulations have moved to recognition
of Revenue or premiums over the contract
period and similarly whatever
acquisition cost or cost of sourcing
that companies incurred they will also
be allowed to be uh amortised over the
contract period again as I said a
favorable enabling regulatory
environment environment change over a
longer term perspective so if I were to
kind of s the combine of 102.7 for this
quarter 3 includes the effect of that
particular change if I were to take that
effect and look at it on a business as
usual basis the combin ratio would have
got reported at 10 12.3% so it has had a
4% impact on the overall combine but
having said that to your point on how do
we see the road ahead I think pretty
much as I talked about I think what we
are seeing is clearly a declining uh com
trajectory for for Isis Lombard and
going forward if the industry kind of
continues to respond favorably uh while
there have been if you look at the half
year of course that we have seen an
adverse change in the overall combin for
the market but assuming the market
remains sensible I think definitely
there is no reason why we should not be
able to see an improvement in Combined
from the current numbers as well
[Music]